Guide to the Thomas Rain Crowe Papers, 1965-2020 RL.10018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Addition (2015-0100), 1960s-2015
  - Personal Materials
    - Personal documents, undated (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
      Expired passport and driver's license.
    - Smoky Mountain High School teaching, 2014-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - George Scarborough Award, Mountain Heritage Literary Festival, 2013 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - Contests/awards submissions and correspondence, 2000s (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - Eco Arts Award, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - Wilderness Society, 2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - Canary Coalition, 2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
    - Events/press for TRC, 2012-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 3)
      Includes flyers, correspondence, and other materials from TRC appearances, performances, and attendance at various community events.
    - The Silver Maple Conspiracy, by Avram Friedman, inscribed to TRC (Box Acc. 15/100: 5)
    - Far from the Centers of Ambition (Box Acc. 15/100: 5)
    - Piotr Klafkowski's Cztowiek i kultury w obliczu zagrozen, referencing TRC, 2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 5)
    - Golf scoresheets, 2010-2014; undated (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-2015
    - Correspondence with "well-known authors/firends", 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - "Literary letters", 1978-1980s (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Andrei Codrescu, 1992 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Nan Watkins, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Carolyn Toben, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Joe Napora, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Philip Daughtry, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Bobi Jones, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Neeli Cherkovski, 2013-2014 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Alessandra Brava, 2013-2015 (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with John Lane, 1986-1992; 2013-2015; 2 folders (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - Correspondence with Anne Hammond (Chapel), 1970s-1980s (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
    - General correspondence, 2013-2015; 11 folders (Box Acc. 15/100: 4)
  - Photographs
    - Baby Beat Generation photo album from France tour (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Miscellaneous photo albums, 1996; undated (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Miscellaneous photos, including Cherokee reunion, college, 1957-1984 (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Miscellaneous photos of TRC and others, 1980s-2000s; 4 folders (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - TRC public performances, 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - TRC and Lucia Picaza, 1994-1995 (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - TRC and the Boatrockers, 1997-2008 (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - TRC and the Boatrockers Thief of Words tour, 2007 (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Zoro's Field manuscript/book miscellaneous photos, 1960s-2000s; 3 folders (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Jackson Co., NC, miscellaneous photos, 1990s (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - Fern Hill Records/New Native Press "Against Information" concert photos, 1996 (Box Acc. 15/100: 6)
    - TRC at Lees-Mcrae College, by photographer Michael Joslin, 2010; Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 0.32 gigabytes; 10 files. (Box Acc. 15/100: 1)
    - TRC and Carolyn Toben Book Tour, 2013; Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 1 gigabyte; 122 files. (Box Acc. 15/100: 1)
    - TRC at the Blue Ridge School, 2010; Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 10 megabytes; 7 images. (Box Acc. 15/100: 1)
    - TRC at John's Cabin, by photographer Olenicki, 2005; Disk image derived from optical disc. Approximately 0.25 gigabytes; 110 files. (Box Acc. 15/100: 1)
- Addition (2017-0022), 1950s-2017; 1
  Electronic records in this series have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room.
  - Correspondence, 1970-2016; 1
    - Ann Lansing, 2008 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Art cards from Ken Long, 2015-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Gary Snyder and Pete Townshend, 1991; undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Letters and interviews: Thomas Berry and Thomas Crowe, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Michael Davitt, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - High profile writers, 2015-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Young poets: Matt MacDonald and Joe Provenzano, 2015-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Letters from Welsh friends, poets, and publishers, 1993-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - General correspondence, 1970-2016; 7 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
  - General Business, 1970s-2016; 2
    - The Boatrockers, 2005-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Canary Coalition, 2001-2016; 2 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Canary Coalition/Air Aid 2001, 2000s; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Copyright/Misc. (info and forms), 1970s-1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - The Dawson Agency/ Publisher Inquiries, 2004 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Koi Fish operation, finances et. al., 2010-2011 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Fern Hill Records, 1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - CD Projects/Fern Hill Records, 1995-2003 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 2)
    - Fern Hill Records/ T. Crowe and Nan Watkins "The King of Bells", 1996-1998 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Local media and publicity contacts, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999-2016; undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Miscellaneous publisher info, etc, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - New England performance tour, 1997 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Rare books for sale, 1999-2000 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Solarize WNC, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Tape distribution, 1990s-2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - UGA Press, payments and accounting, 2000s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - WNC Alliance misc., 1980s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
  - New Native Press, 1970s-2016; 3
    - Amazon.com Advantage, 1998 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Baby Beat Generation Misc., 2006 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Celtic anthology: Writing the Wind, 1990s-2000s; 6 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Jeff Davis Natures, 2006 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Distribution, 1990s-2000s; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - ISBN and Library of Congress information and applications, 1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 3)
    - Mailing List, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 8)
      One plastic box containing index cards with written addresses.
    - Miscellaneous business, 1970s-2010s; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Orders and sales, 1995-2016; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Oversized materials, 1970s-2016 (Folder Acc. 2017/022: Ovsz. Folder 1)
      Oversized materials including posters, broadsides, production materials, and some artwork.
    - Oversized materials, 1970s-2016 (Folder Acc. 2017/022: Ovsz. Folder 2)
    - Oversized publicity materials, 2000s (Tube 1)
    - Pourqoui Je Suis Un Monstre, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Potential book files, marginalized languages, 2000s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Printer, 1996-1997 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Publicity and promotional materials, 1990-1995 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Raking Leaves in a Hurricane, Michael Revere, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Red Lipstick, 2005 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Review copies/slips, 2007 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Reviews and miscellaneous, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Review journals and bookstores, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Possible book projects, 2010-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Promotion and distribution, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Sales, orders, and returns, 1999-2010 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - John Sauter, Elegy Epitaphs, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Wake party, 2016 December (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Why I am a Monster, 1990; undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
  - Personal Materials, 1950s-2016; 4
    - Addresses for writers, friends, and acquaintances in San Francisco, 1970s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Awards, 1958-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Artwork, 1950s-1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 8)
    - Business cards, address book, bank account books, San Francisco, 1970s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Calendars, day books, address books, 1977-2016; 9 items (Box Acc. 2017/022: 8)
    - Childhood, 1957-1964 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Resume, portfolio, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - David Dawson, 1988-2000 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Furman University, 1960s-1970s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - High school and college miscellaneous, 1965-1973 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 4)
    - Letters, clippings from high school and college, 1967-1973 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-2010s; 3 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Outdoors pioneer award, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Oversized materials, 1970s-2016 (Folder Acc. 2017/022: Ovsz. Folder 1)
    - Oversized materials, 1970s-2016 (Folder Acc. 2017/022: Ovsz. Folder 2)
    - Report cards, 1958-1967 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Readings, presentations, 1980s-2016; 2 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - San Francisco years, Beats/Baby beats miscellaneous, 1970s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Thank you letters from grade school children, 1978-2007 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
  - Teaching, 1998-2016; undated; 5
    - Jackson County Department of Ageing, 2016; 2 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - J. C. Campbell Folk School, 1998 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - The Mountain programs and lectures, 2006 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - The new best poetry group, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - NC Arboretum classes, 2006-2016; 5 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Reuters center for seniors course, 2006 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Western Carolina University Course, 2000; 3 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Exquisite corpse poems by high schoolers, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
  - Translations, 1970s-2010s; 6
    - Boris Vian, 1970s-2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Jigar/versions, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Misc. translation materials, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Poetry of Marc Ichall, 1973-2005 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Terraque (Land and Water), 1998-2010 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
    - Translations into french, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 5)
  - Writings, 1962-2017; undated; 7
    - Above the Waterfall/ Ron Rash book review, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Barbarian Days book review, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Bardic book/ Ghost Pony Press, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Bob Dylan Nobel Prize rebuttal, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Book of Words, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Book project, saw mill shack, 1990s-2010s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Do Not Call Death the Inner Trees this Holy Body, 2017 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Death of Poetry in America, 1975 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Editing projects, misc., 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - End of Eden miscellaneous texts, digital materials, 2007; Logical files exported from one USB. (Box Acc. 2017/022: 9)
      Electronic records have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room.
    - Essays to develop, 1980s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Ethics of Dust: articles, essays, and reviews, 1974-1998; 2 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Generations anthology, 2011-2015; 3 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Gold Eaters book review, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Go Set a Watchman, Harper Lee book review, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Half-Earth, E. O. Wilson book review, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Home is… essay for Hub City anthology, 2014 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Idea for Children books, Dahna Massey drawings, 1985-1986 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - An interview with artist Lynfield Ott, 1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Interview with Bear Rineheart of Need to Breathe, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Is there an Arts Community?, 1996 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - It's our Turn Now, 60s generation coming of age in 2000, 2000s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Issa book, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Journal, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Katvah journal, digital project, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Last in the Line: The Life of Amoneeta Sequoya, 1962-2003 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - The Laugherne Papers: The Lost Poems of Dylan Thomas (travel novel), 1993 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Learning to Dance, 1973-2015; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Left handed writing: a spiritual practice with questions and answers, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - New Native: Writing in Place, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Newspaper interview/Argentina, "Endangered Languages", 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Novel outlines, 1990; undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Oil and Marble, book review, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Novel: Sourwood (a story of backwoods life in modern Appalachia), undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Over the Plain Houses, book review, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Paris Red, book review, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Photos for Crack Light, undated (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Photos for Spoleto freelance interviews and articles, 1980s-1990s (Box Acc. 2017/022: 6)
    - Practical Epiphanies, Crossing the Water, 1991-2000; 2 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Publications, 2005-2016; 8 Volumes (Box Acc. 2017/022: 8)
    - Reviews and blurbs for books, 2015 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Songs file, 1994 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Thomas, digital materials, 2000-2007; Logical files exported from one USB. (Box Acc. 2017/022: 9)
      Contains many manuscript drafts of various titles.
    - Too Many People/ Childrens' book, 2011 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Tuskagee History book article, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - The Wake Up Man, 1996-2005 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - The Watcher, 2014 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Water from the Moon, 2001 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - You Get What You Give Up, A Life Story, 1996 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-2017; 7 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
  - Wrtings by Others, 1976-2016; undated; 8
    - Pancho Aguila, 1976-1977 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Linda Bledsoe, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Barbara Ann Carver Hunt, 1996-1997 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Philip Daughtry, 1995-2004; 3 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - John Lane novel ch. 1, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Brent Martin, 2009-2012 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Assaad Mounzer project, 2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Joe Napora, 1991-2010; undated; 4 folders (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Ted Pope, 2008-2009 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Gene Ragland, 2015-2016 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Brian Roberts, 2013 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Lala Ingram Wade, Memoir, 1976 (Box Acc. 2017/022: 7)
    - Ken Wainio, digital materials, 1996; Logical files exported from one USB. (Box Acc. 2017/022: 9)
      Starfuck: a cyber-novel
- Addition (2018-0181), 1958-2018
  Original audiovisual and electronic media are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to review an inventory and request the production of use or viewing copies.
  - Audiovisual materials: cassettes, CDs, other media (Box AV 1)
    Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services to request an audiovisual inventory and the production of use copies.
  - Electronic media: USB, CDs, DVDs, other media (Box ER 1)
    Original electronic media is closed to use. Contact Research Services to request an inventory of media in this collection and to request the production of viewing copies for the Rubenstein Reading Room terminal.
  - General correspondence, 1980-2018; 3 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Correspondence with goddaughter Califia Suntree, 1987-2017; 3 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Dea Zullo over San Francisco book, 2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Justin Blackburn (poet), 2017-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Lori Pavich, and poetry, 2017-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - General email correspondence (printouts), 2000s-2010s; 5 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Publicity, clippings, events, 1972-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Photographs of Dylan's Boathouse, undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Nan Watkins, 1989-2018; 6 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 2)
  - Notes from Nan Watkins to TRC, 1989-2018; 7 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 2)
  - Lynn Ott book project, 1958-1993; 4 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Ed Lipman book project, poetry, clippings, 1974-1975 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - The Stranger in the Woods book review: draft and published version, 2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Saw Mill Shack book project: draft introduction and photocopies, 1999-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Zoro's Field (monthly installment of book), 2003-2005 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Unpublished poems, 1987-2001 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Water from the Moon corrected draft, 2001 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Writing in Place book idea and essays, undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Inside the Rainbow: children's book project draft with edits, 1985-2005 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - "Unified field theory in relation to relativity based on synchronicity and the physics of love," notes, 1979-2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Grant King book project, 2016-2017; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Asheville Poetry Wall project, 2016 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Farm and garden file (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Beat Literary Archive project correspondence, 2016 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Katuah Journal digital archive project correspondence, publicity, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Reviews of writings by others, written by TRC, 2017-2018; 7 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Poetry Out Loud competition, Smoky Mountain High School, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - UNC Asheville video interview event, correspondence, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - TRC preface for Hawk on Wire, by Scott Starbuck, 2016-2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - NC poet laureate nomination, 2017-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Appalachian Online: celebrating the birth of Appalachian studies (TRC as panelist), 2017 Oct. (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Trip to Furman University, talks, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous drafts, 1987-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - TRC foreword for book by Don Hendershot, 2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - TRC edits on book by Assaad Mounzer, 2017-2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous flyers for New Native Press (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - NC Arboretum classes, 2017-2018; 4 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Book Exchange writers group, 2016-2018; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Waynesboro High School 50th class reunion, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 3)
  - Email correspondence with Dee Stribling, 2017-2018; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Email correspondence with Matt McDonald (Scottish poet), 2017-2018; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - A skeleton key to Zoro's Field, by Diana Kirk: drafts, correspondence with edits, 2010 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Speaking in Tongues: Postmodernism and the War with Words: proposal and draft samples, 2009-2011 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Working into Wisdom: interviews with women in the arts: draft interviews, 2010 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Practical Epiphanies: Putting the Muse to Work draft, undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Important authors and influences for TRC (as declared by him), 1970s-2000s; 2 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Starting from San Francisco: draft and copy of book; book launch, reading, correspondence, 2018; 5 folders (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - In Afterglow: Poems 1987-2001: unpublished original draft with corrections (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Correspondence with Arthur Nusbaum, 2015-2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Transcript of audio interview with Third Mind Books, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Photographs (with labels) (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Liberty High School (Bethlehem, Pennsylvania) high school diploma, 1968 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Furman University B.A. diploma, 1972 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 4)
  - Losing a Language: TRC contribution to anthology Appalachia: Stay or Go?, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Jejune: TRC contribution to Overthrowing Capitalism Vol. 5, 2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Picking Blueberries in the Rain: TRC contribution to The Hills are Alive poetry anthology, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Native Tongue: TRC contribution to Best Creative Nonfiction of the South, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - TRC's planner/datebook, 2017 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - TRC journal: Baby Beat Generation tour and engagements, 2006 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - TRC journal with poetry drafts, undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Interview with TRC by Floriane Martins (including Spanish), undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous works by Michael O'Brien, 1990 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Burnout to Engagement, by Assaad Mounzer (with TRC edits), 2018 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Hawk on Wire, with inscription for TRC, by Scott Starbuck (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Goodbye to the Animal People, by George Schricker: notes and draft, 2010 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Only the Dance, with inscription to TRC, by Christine Lassiter, undated (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Chronik, by Gil Ott, 1976 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - The Iron Mountain Review, Vol. 4, No. 2, 1988 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Resolutions in Spring, by Alexander Kohav and Irving Stettmer, 1977 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Paper Air journal, Vol. 1, No. 1, 3, 1976; 1978 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - We Speak: Selected poems from First Annual Nevada County Women's Art Festival, 1980 May (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Letter from Cuba by Ricardo Cambridge, and additional materials, 1999 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
  - Mogon, the Giant One, by George Schricker, 1986 (Box Acc. 18/181: Box 5)
- Addition (2019-0178), 1994-2019
  - Electronic media: USBs, CDS, DVDs, and other media (Box AV 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2019
    - General correspondence, 1997-2019; 9 folders (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
  - General Business, 1994-2002
    - TRC and the Boatrockers: playlists, correspondence, performance notes, 1994-2002; 3 folders (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
  - New Native Press bibliography, invoices, letterhead (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
  - Personal Materials, 2018-2019
    - Tyler Kinnear wedding, TRC officiating, 2019 June (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Pocket calendar, 2018 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
  - Teaching, 2019
    - ARB/Book Exchange Group, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - NC Arboretum class, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Wormsloe Gathering for Southern Writers, 2019 November (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
  - Writings, 2001-2019
    - The Book of Words (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Driving the Green Road, 2018-2019; 2 folders (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Poems for gallery show in Asheville "Poems and Politics", 2019 May (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Mountains Piled Upon Mountains anthology, University of West Virginia, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Mountains Piled Upon Mountains anthology book, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Book reviews in Smoky Mountain News, 2018-2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - Preface for the Fire of Darkness, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - The Inner Trees, Selected Poems by Yvonn Goll production materials, 2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - The Inner Trees, Selected Poems by Yvonn Goll drafts, 2019; 4 folders (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)
    - The Inner Trees, Selected Poems by Yvonn Goll correspondence, 2017-2019 (Box Acc. 19/178: Box 1)